Guide to the Buffalo Bill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Buffalo Bill papers
1894-1916
WA MSS S-197
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.5
(1 box)
Mostly correspondence with Buffalo Bill and a document regarding his Wild West Show.
Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unspecified, please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist mainly of correspondence with Buffalo Bill, and are accompanied by a document regarding his Wild West Show.
Courts -- United States; Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917; Chamberlin, John F.; Chappell, R. Valentine; Coe, William Robertson, 1869-1955; Heimer, Albert; Heimer, Elsie; Meyer, Frank, fl. 1894; Russell, James Emmett, 1879; Russell, Michael R.; Steele, William R.; Thurber, Henry T.; Buffalo Bill's Wild West and Pawnee Bill's Great Far East (Show)
- Box and folder list
  - Chamberlin, John F.
    - 2 ALS to W. F. Cody. Fort Monroe, Va., 1896 Apr-Jun (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      1896 Apr 30, Jun 21.
  - Cody, William Frederick
    - ALS to "My Dear Davenport". Natchez, Miss., 1900 Oct 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Accompanied by TLS of transmittal from R. Valentine Chappell to William Robertson Coe.
    - ALS to James Russell. Milan, Italy., 1916 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Col. Cody's Wild West. Route & Address., 1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 42 letters and telegrams to M. R. Russell. V.p., 1893-98 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - 6 ALS & 1 TLS to William Robertson Coe. Denver and New York., 1910 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Heimer, Elsie
    - ALS to James Russell. Cody, Wyo., 1906 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Signed: Elsie and Albert Heimer. On p. [2] is a note "My dear Jim" signed "Mother".
  - Russell, Michael R.
    - TL (copy) to Meyer Frank. Deadwood, S.D., 1894 Feb 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - TL (copy) to W. F. Cody. Deadwood, S.D., 1896 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Recommends Col. W. R. Steele for a federal judgeship.
    - TL (copy) to W. F. Cody. Deadwood, S.D., 1897 Apr 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Thurber, Henry T.
    - TLS to W. F. Cody., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Acknowledges Pres. McKinley's receipt of Cody's recommendation of W. R. Steele.